<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Polyglot</title>
 <link href="http://untra.github.com/polyglot/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://untra.github.com/polyglot/"/>
 <updated>2015-09-23T19:14:13-06:00</updated>
 <id>http://untra.github.com/polyglot</id>
 <author>
   <name>Samuel Volin</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Presenting Polyglot</title>
   <link href="http://untra.github.com/polyglot/2015/08/19/presenting-polyglot/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://untra.github.com/polyglot/2015/08/19/presenting-polyglot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After months of work and refinement, I am proud to present Polyglot: a i18n plugin for &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; sites that &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to cater their content to multiple languages and audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are other multi-language plugins for Jekyll, Polyglot is special. Polyglot takes care of the typical cruftwork normally left to developers to manage (such as wrangling urls and ensuring consistent sitemaps) while providing efficient and simple tools Jekyll developers can utilize into SEO and fast-tracked content aggregation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Relativized Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, a multi-language static site or blog had to keep delicate track of what language each relative link the site was serving. It was all too easy for a developer to stumble, and foreign language visitors would quickly get lost in untranslated content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polyglot automatically relativizes the urls for each language you want your site to build for. This way your french website stays isolated from your english one (as long your french website stays french)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Fallback Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you &lt;em&gt;don&amp;#39;t&lt;/em&gt; have translated or multilingual content, the site will still build with the content you do have. When you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; have translated or multilingual content, the site will build using that content. Simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitemaps stay consistent across all languages, and translated stays in the site it was built for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Rich Content Translation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rich language content is normally hard to implement. Short strings or language dependent banners are typically hard for a Jekyll website to keep consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Except when it&amp;#39;s this easy&lt;/em&gt;. In your config.yml, just store your strings as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;hello&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;en&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;Hello!&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;es&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;¡hola!&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;fr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;Bonjour!&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;de&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p-Indicator&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;l-Scalar-Plain&quot;&gt;Guten Tag!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and in your liquid, just call:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;{{ site.hello[site.active_lang]}}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;produces:
&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
¡hola!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Fast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polyglot will build you multi-language website just as fast as it will build your default language website. Polyglot runs with a minimal overhead by &lt;em&gt;simultaneously&lt;/em&gt; building all languages of your website at the same time. This means your website build time won&amp;#39;t be a function of how many languages you need to support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing Hyde</title>
   <link href="http://untra.github.com/polyglot/2013/12/28/introducing-hyde/"/>
   <updated>2013-12-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://untra.github.com/polyglot/2013/12/28/introducing-hyde</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hyde is a brazen two-column &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; theme that pairs a prominent sidebar with uncomplicated content. It&amp;#39;s based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpoole.com&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt;, the Jekyll butler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Built on Poole&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poole is the Jekyll Butler, serving as an upstanding and effective foundation for Jekyll themes by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mdo&quot;&gt;@mdo&lt;/a&gt;. Poole, and every theme built on it (like Hyde here) includes the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Jekyll setup included (layouts, config, &lt;a href=&quot;/404&quot;&gt;404&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/atom.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;, posts, and &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;example page&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly design and development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily scalable text and component sizing with &lt;code&gt;rem&lt;/code&gt; units in the CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for a wide gamut of HTML elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related posts (time-based, because Jekyll) below each post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syntax highlighting, courtesy Pygments (the Python-based code snippet highlighter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hyde features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the features of Poole, Hyde adds the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidebar includes support for textual modules and a dynamically generated navigation with active link support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two orientations for content and sidebar, default (left sidebar) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/lanyon#reverse-layout&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/a&gt; (right sidebar), available via &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/hyde#themes&quot;&gt;Eight optional color schemes&lt;/a&gt;, available via &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/hyde#readme&quot;&gt;Head to the readme&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Browser support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hyde is by preference a forward-thinking project. In addition to the latest versions of Chrome, Safari (mobile and desktop), and Firefox, it is only compatible with Internet Explorer 9 and above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hyde is developed on and hosted with GitHub. Head to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/hyde&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; for downloads, bug reports, and features requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What's Jekyll?</title>
   <link href="http://untra.github.com/polyglot/2012/02/06/whats-jekyll/"/>
   <updated>2012-02-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://untra.github.com/polyglot/2012/02/06/whats-jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a static site generator, an open-source tool for creating simple yet powerful websites of all shapes and sizes. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/blob/master/README.markdown&quot;&gt;the project&amp;#39;s readme&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a simple, blog aware, static site generator. It takes a template directory [...] and spits out a complete, static website suitable for serving with Apache or your favorite web server. This is also the engine behind GitHub Pages, which you can use to host your project’s page or blog right here from GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s an immensely useful tool and one we encourage you to use here with Hyde.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out more by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;visiting the project on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
